

Viktorija Radčenko

Port folio http://viktorijenko.github.io





vradcenko@gmail.com



+37066272359



Viktorija Radčenko

I am a freelance WEB and Graphic Designer looking for an opportunity to join a company for a full-time position. I have 6 years of experience in sales and customer relationship management. An empathetic approach helps me understand user needs and goals as well as find user-centered solutions to problems. Can-do is my motto!

Work Experience

Freelance WEB and Graphic Designer

June 2022 - Present

UX/UI Design Intern, TietoEvry UAB

July - August 2022

Designing tasks from start to finish; conducting research, analysing competitors, creating user personas; collaborating with the business analyst in identifying problems and user needs; creating sitemaps; prototyping and testing with end users; presenting UI mockups and prototypes to developers; using an established design system; working in a cross-functional team using Agile/Scrum methods.

Fieldsales Executive, DHL Lietuva UAB

Jan 2020 - Sep 2021

Managing and developing the assigned customer territory mostly through F2F meetings; searching for new prospects and opportunities; negotiating and establishing customer contracts; monitoring customer performance, loyalty and business fluctuation while ensuring their needs are recognized and met.

Telesales Executive, DHL Lietuva UAB

Jun 2018 - Dec 2019

Assigned customer territory management and development; KPI and sales pipeline management using various CRM systems; consulting customers on day-to-day questions: price enquiries, claim handling, shipment tracking, operational issues.

Direct Marketing Executive, DHL Lietuva UAB

Jan 2017 - May 2018

Market analysis; marketing campaigns for ad-hoc clients; internal and external communication on new products and services; email marketing, newsletters.

Sales Lead Qualifier, DHL Lietuva UAB

Jan 2016 - Dec 2016

Outgoing calls, searching for potential customers; onboarding of new customers.

Education & Courses

Google UX Design Course, Coursera

September 2022 - Present

WEB Design, UX/UI course, CodeAcademy

Apr - Jun 2022

User Experience Design Essentials - Adobe XD UI UX Design, Udemy

Feb - Mar 2022

Digital Skills: User Experience, Accenture

Jan 2022

Introduction to User Experience Design, Coursera

Law & Management, Mykolas Romeris University and University of Bordeaux,

2009 - 2016

Bachelor's and Master's Degree

Tools Skills

Figma WEB design, Mobile design, Responsive Design

Adobe Xd UX Research (interviews, surveys, competitive analysis)

Sketch User Flows, Site maps, Information Architecture

Adobe Illustrator User centered design, Design thinking

Adobe Photoshop Sketching, wireframing, prototyping

VS Code Visual Design: Style Guides, Iconography, Typography

Microsoft Office Design systems

Teams, Zoom, Slack Basics of coding (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)

Jira, Asana, Notion Product management according to Agile/Scrum

Languages

Lithuanian - native **English** - professional proficiency **Russian** - intermediate